hello everyone this is Frank defreitis
and welcome to another week of whole
talk for the week of December 13th
1999. I have a request that I'd like to
make to the holotalk listeners and had
something happen here in the studio
within the last week you'll notice that
my annual Fanta show that I put up for
everyone out there who has kids are just
like Santa on on their own as adults I
do that on whole talk for one week yeah
each year
it's been up for two weeks and there's a
reason for that and the reason is that I
accidentally
trashed every whole talk show that I've
done for this year so far they are gone
I do not have any of the shows in fact
the show that I had to go up that week
was actually in the folder and that was
trashed as well and I realized I can't
get that one back
but what I'm wondering is is there
anyone out there
who not only just listens the whole talk
but actually downloads the show and
perhaps puts the show into a folder and
keeps the past Holo talk shows if you
are out there would you please email me
and let me know if you have any shows
from the past season since we started
right after Labor Day and let me know
what shows you have if you just have one
show I'll take one show if you have a
bunch of shows I'll take a bunch of
shows but send me an email and let me
know if you have any shows that you
could attach to an email and send to me
I'd like to get the archive page up in
fact that's how I found out that they
were missing was I was beginning to I
had this year's show on to the archive
page and I had no folder in the past
I've put everything on zip disk because
the past two years I have the complete
collection on zip discs but for some
reason this year since I started up in
sept member I would just take a show and
Stewart in one of the folders on the
hard drive
I have absolutely no idea how I took
this folder and just trashed it and it's
gone and what's really strange is I have
Norton utilities that
file saver which can allow you to go
back in and retrieve the files but when
I do any multimedia production on the
machine I disable that which is fine
because you can turn it back on after
you're finished with the multimedia
production and it doesn't use any
resources
for a regular thing and for regular
everyday use of the computer
but it does tie up resources and
processing power and
when you have multimedia production
going on so I usually disable it so I
did not re-enable it after I did some
multimedia production and when I trashed
it it wasn't registered by a file saver
so I had no way of going back in and
possibly extracting any of the files off
of the hard drive that's there so if you
have one of the past Hall talk shows I
would appreciate it even if it's just
one show maybe there's a number of you
who have different shows that you liked
and you kept could you send me an email
and let me know and we'll get those past
shows back up
so needless to say this week is just
myself and I'll be starting up guests
again next week with the next Holo talk
show which will begin on December 20th
and run for
there so we'll have a guest coming on
next week
other news you may have been on the
mailing list you may not have been on
the mailing list you know it's my style
here at holotalk for the past two and a
half years that I really don't sell
anything on this show I basically just
do the show but I do I would like to
announce that fam Savage and I are now
in production of our laser units and
they are available and this basically
grew out of the request or a number of
requests from different people involved
with holography when we were working
with our 35 milliwatt laser system that
we put together and specifically the
power Drive Unit that's hooked up to the
Mitsubishi 35 millilit diode and we got
a number of emails from someone saying
if I paid you would you put one of these
together for me
so we thought you know maybe we should
build a few of these and as you know if
you're on the email list we've been
working on this for a while we have a
number of different things available a
number of different options I imagine
there's four options really that you can
choose from to
have one of these inexpensive relatively
high power laser systems to do
holography in your own holographic
Studio or lab
we have a web page up now DNS lasers we
have someone working with us that's
going to incorporate it so we're going
to be DNS lasers Incorporated shortly
but there's a few different options that
you can order you can order the actual
plans and schematic uh
which you can build the system yourself
and the schematic is to the power Drive
Unit that you can put that together and
another option is you can get the power
Drive Unit and a
separate chip that we have inside of
that power Drive Unit to power the laser
diode and you will need that chip with
option one or option two but with option
two you can order the chip with the with
the plans at the same time with option
one you can order just the plans and
then order the chip at a later time
option three is a complete kit all of
the components that you need including
the 35 milliwatt Mitsubishi diode along
with the barrel and the collimating
Optics and everything you need to build
the Drive Unit yourself
of course option four is um the fact
that you can buy the completely
assembled unit where you take it out of
the box and you're ready to shoot
Holograms so right away so those things
are available now and I'm happy to be
able to announce that I'm not going to
be plugging this on each show but uh
I just wanted to remind everyone that
you know we've been working on this for
quite some time and we're happy to be
able to bring this to you finally uh
this week and we do have quite a bit of
interest in that if you're not on the
email list you can definitely get on
that for further updates I spoke with
John Claire earlier actually I didn't
speak with John Claire he sent me an
email I asked him to give me an update
on what he's doing with the uh multiple
laser pointer uh Holograms and he's
still experimenting uh with that and
he's had some very nice results using
several laser pointers to create
Holograms where they're power is
combined
and the Hologram is shot from that what
he's going to do now he's moving off in
the direction where he's going to buy
raw diodes and attach the fiber directly
either to the window itself on the diode
or remove that window entirely and
attach the fiber and have the laser
light travel through the fiber in that
way so we're looking for some very
exciting stuff with the fiber optics and
Steve Michael is working on the fiber
optic experiments as well and we will
have further updates on that as time
goes on I want further holotalk shows
also Dave Hodges Dave and I did speak
today on the telephone for quite some
time and Dave has had excellent results
as he reported on the phone to me using
the slavage
pfg03m
holographic film and
you'll remember that we spoke on several
past Hall talk shows about using the
pfg01 which is a little bit more
sensitive and and probably falls into
the sensitivity range of the type of
Photography that amateur and hobbyists
do because you know we're using
relatively low power if you're using a
pointer you're five milliwatts or below
or even 10 or 15 millilites is fairly
low power so the PFG 01 certainly uh
fits into that very nicely but what was
really surprising about this is Dave
Hodges was using the PFG 03n which is
not
is responsive it's uh usually we would
think that the exposure times would be
much too long for low power helium neon
lasers to give good results on that but
he said the the shots that he has done
with that Emulsion so far has been
absolutely gorgeous absolutely gorgeous
and what's really very very interesting
about this is that he's working with
five milliwatts in his uh Studio
which he has in his home and he
eventually wants to do eight by ten so
what he's doing with his experiments is
he's taking the laser light
and expanding that to an 8 by 10 area
and then shooting four by five film in
that eight by ten spread so basically
what this gives him is an indication of
how nice a neat by 10 hologram would be
without having to use the 8x10 film and
he's just uh
craving you know the results that he's
had so far with this and he is using the
uh the check by notes here to make sure
I have everything correct he is using
the gp2 developing regimen which is
available from both photographers
formulary and also into graph and now of
course the film is available from a
number of locations as well
thumb into graph and from the fourth
dimension holographics and a number of
different places but if you do go back
to the link page that I have at hello
world you can get a listing of different
suppliers of that film as well and I
would be interested to hear from anyone
else who's using the PFG
03m because apparently that seems to be
working out very well at his exposure
time he's saying is about 10 times the
exposure time of the pfg01
pfg03 and it doesn't seem to have that
much of an effect increasing that
exposure time 10 times for him so maybe
something to look at and he says the
diffraction efficiency is so much higher
than your whole grains are so bright
they exhibit so much depth
that I think this probably wants you
know a further investigation and his
development regimen let me suggests that
you do not
excuse me agitate the uh
film in the developer what he did was
actually just drop the film into the
development tray and leave it sit there
undisturbed for 15 minutes it took to
develop it in
in gp2 developer so that's a little
update on that another possibility with
a very high diffraction efficiency and
very good results using low power five
milliwatts on the pfg03m reported by
Dave Hodges who's been working with that
in fact his adults were from a laser
spread that would have covered an 8 by
10 inch piece of film so that's very
encouraging
excuse me
not too much more news this week so
once again if you know
of anyone who could send a few of the
past total talk shows to me I would be
very
very happy to receive them and get them
up on the archive page so that others
can enjoy some of the past shows and if
I don't get a response from anyone and
no one has the shows then that's that's
it they're lost to history unless
someone out there has them and is not
listening to the show this week and
maybe a few weeks or a few months down
the line and
asking a world where are the shows and
oh I have a couple of them I can send
them to you so we may not be at a total
loss but I'd appreciate it if anyone has
a show
to please email me let me know what
shows you have and then I'll make
arrangements to receive those shows I'm
going to attach files to emails from you
so once again this is Frankie Freitas
thank you for tuning in to another week
of whole talk it was a short show we had
some interesting news on here
um
but we'll get back to our guests next
week and I look forward to continuing
the broadcast well into the year 2000 uh
bringing you news and information about
the fields of lasers and holography so I
will say have a great week and don't
forget to tune in next week and every
week to hollow talk this is Frankie
Freitas take care